in the late 1970s Anastasio Samosa the
dictator of the small Central American
country of Nicaragua was overthrown
Samosa was overthrown and was replaced
by a group called The sandinistas they
had been called the Sandinista Rebels
and they were led by a man named
Danielle Ortega Ortega was a communist
he called himself a socialist but he was
pro-soviet and pro Cuban and received a
great deal of aid from both of those
countries the United States at the time
was led by President Ronald Reagan and
as historians will tell you Reagan was
absolutely obsessed with Communism and
he promoted something called the Domino
Theory the Domino Theory held that if
one single Central American country fell
to the Communists the other countries in
Central America would fall like dominoes
leading right up to the US border So
Reagan and the people around him set out
to stop the Communists from taking
control of Nicaragua they did that
by announcing their support for the
Contra Rebels the contras were
conservatives right-wingers and some
cases even fascists or Military Officers
who were disgruntled with the with
Ortega they decided to take to the
jungles with American weapons and fight
the new communist government the problem
with that though was that the Democratic
controlled Congress at the time passed
an amendment that forbade the government
from spending any money to provide
weapons ammunition or weapon systems to
the Contra Rebels so how do you get
around that well there was a director at
the National Security Council at the
time by the name of Colonel Oliver North
North decided to take this thing on on
his own he did not report back to his
superiors at the Pentagon he worked
closely with the CIA and here's the plan
they came up with they would sell
weapons to America's arch enemy Iran the
weapons would be paid for in cash the
cash would be turned over to a Saudi
businessman and arms dealer named Adnan
Kashi Kashi would put the money in a
bank in Cyprus and then would transfer
it to the Contra Rebels there was a
middleman there of course it was a
series of arms dealers mostly in Romania
Bulgaria and uh and elsewhere around the
world that were able to provide These
Arms with little to no notice uh coming
to the attention of any body who follows
these things keep in mind also that this
entire operation was off the books it
was supposed to be secret not just
secret from the public of course but
secret from the Congressional oversight
committees secret from the president of
the United States himself secret from
the FBI and from the Pentagon nobody was
supposed to know about this except
Oliver North and the CIA and so the CIA
involved Adnan Kashi because he was was
an old friend of the organization he
became a billionaire by selling arms
around the world what better person to
do something like this somebody who
already has a lot of money somebody
who's not going to raise eyebrows by
transferring hundreds of millions of
dollars somebody who's going to use
foreign Banks just as a matter of course
so imagine Adnan koki takes money from
the Iranians puts that money in a
cypriate bank transfers the money from
the cypriot bank to International arms
manufacturers takes the arms from those
manufacturers turns them over to the CIA
the CIA puts them on unmarked unlicensed
and unregistered planes and sends them
to the Contra rebels in Nicaragua it
sounded like the perfect idea in fact it
was a terrible idea and it was a
violation of the law many many laws but
Adnan koki was someone who the CIA could
trust to keep his mouth shut take his
10% commission and do as he was told in
the end the Iranians got weapons they
paid cash the cash was used to buy more
weapons that were given to the Contra
Rebels so the contras began fighting
Daniel Ortega and the sandinistas the US
meanwhile was doing things like mining
the harbors of uh of managa the capital
of Nicaragua to put pressure on the
sandinistas and the fight was really
raging in the jungle at at the same time
by the mid1 1980s cocaine began arriving
in the United States ostensibly from
Colombia but really making its way
through Nicaragua now that cocaine for
whatever reason ended up in Los Angeles
and in Los Angeles it was turned into
crack cocaine now we had never heard of
crack cocaine before 1984 and it took
off like wildfire an investigative
journalist by the name of Gary Webb
decided to look into the Advent of the
crack epidemic in Los Angeles and that
investigation led him right back to
Nicaragua so here's what he found he
found that the Contra Rebels were not
one monolithic unit they were divided
into Northern Rebels and Southern Rebels
more importantly he found that the
rebels were largely in the pay of the
CIA Now The Drug Enforcement
Administration was also present in
Nicaragua at the time and remember it's
DEA
job to stop the flow of drugs to the
United States the CIA though doesn't
care about drugs in many cases it's
perfectly happy to allow drugs into the
United States if it helps them to fight
communism or contemporaneously to fight
terrorism drugs are dea's problem the
CIA is not going to trouble itself with
drugs and so these drugs were making
their way to California Gary Webb
traveled to Nicaragua where he
interviewed dozens of Contra Rebels
including Contra leaders he also
interviewed members of the sandanista
government who told him look there's a
drug problem but it has nothing to do
with us it's your people the contras
that are bringing these drugs to the
United States Gary Webb returned to
California with notebooks full of
information and he began to write a
series of articles for the San Jose
Mercury News his investigation resulted
in seven separate articles and in those
articles he said that the drugs were
coming from Nicaragua and making their
way to Los Angeles that there were two
people in particular one was named Oscar
Blandon Oscar Blandon was a senior
Contra leader who was in charge of this
cocaine operation the other was a major
drug importer based in Los Angeles he
also said that the CIA was allowing this
to happen he did not say that this was a
CIA operation although that's how the
CIA took it Gary web said that the CIA
was turning a blind eye and was actually
stying the work that the DEA was trying
to do to keep the drugs out of the
United States as you might imagine this
series of Articles created an absolute
Firestorm especially within the Los
Angeles Times The Washington Post and
the New York Times we now know that as
soon as these articles were published
the Los Angeles Times called together 17
journalists to pick apart and to refute
Gary web's articles now they focused on
things that were Silly and nonsensical
for example web was a little bit weak in
his analysis on the actual origins of
the crack epidemic that's not the point
of the story though the point of the
story was that the CIA was allowing
cocaine into the country the Los Angeles
Times though said well he got it wrong
about Los Angeles crack arrived in Los
Angeles a little bit earlier than Gary
Webb said who cares but this is
something that Gary Webb and the San
Jose Mercury News had to deal with on
the other coast The Washington Post and
the New York Times essentially said on
their front pages that Gary Webb had
made the entire story up uh Walter
pinkis an esteemed reporter for the
Washington Post got the side of the CIA
and put that on the very front page of
the Washington Post saying that none of
this was true this was just an anti- CIA
uh tie raade
and that nobody should pay any attention
to it well Pinkus was wrong Pinkus
probably knew he was wrong but published
anyway the bottom line here is that both
the Washington Post and the New York
Times leapt as quickly as they could to
the defense of the CIA Gary web's
editors then decided to double down they
decided to finance another trip to
Nicaragua that Gary web would take so
that he could answer some of the
questions that these other major
newspapers had so he went to Nicaragua
not once not twice but four times in the
end the paper decided that there wasn't
enough new information to Warrant
another series but they were confident
that Webb had told the truth still on
the very same day the Washington Post
and the New York Times finally wrote a
coordinated article saying that Gary
Webb was a liar that he was a fabricator
and that he should be fired it was then
that the Mercury News decided maybe they
should take a step back from web and
they did in a dispute he ended up Res
signing now the sad postcript to this is
this was a guy who had a storied career
in investigative journalism he was a a
co-winner of the Pulitzer Prize he had
done investigative journalism in
Cincinnati Ohio in Cleveland in Columbus
Ohio and then out to California where he
made a real name for himself in San Jose
but he resigned from that position he
freelanced for a little while he worked
for the state for a few months and then
decided to move to Denver Colorado and
start over but depression overcame him
finally Gary Webb rented a cheap motel
room and reportedly allegedly put a gun
in his mouth and pulled the trigger a
lot of people think that he actually
didn't commit suicide his family does
and the coroner did but there are
questions surrounding his death in the
end it was the CIA the New York Times
The Washington Post in the Los Angeles
Times that ruined him there are
reporters now who have retired from the
LA Times who have spoken publicly about
their effort to ruin Gary Webb and his
career they express regret and they
admit freely that that's exactly what
they did they ruined his career and by
ruining his career they ended his life
later on there were investigations in
Washington the CIA Inspector General
conducted an investigation the justice
department Inspector General conducted
an independent investigation and even
the house permanent select committee on
intelligence conducted investigation and
what did they find they found that
everything Gary web said was true the
sad part of this is that no one at the
CIA was ever prosecuted no one was ever
even fired or suspended for trafficking
cocaine into the United States but
that's how the CIA Works remember the
CIA Mantra is we're the good guys the
good guys don't get punished for doing
their job but Gary Webb was a good guy
and he certainly was punished for doing
his job hey thanks for watching this
report there is so much more that I'd
like to dive into but unfortunately we
can't do that here thanks to heavy
censorship efforts from Big Tech if you
want to explore this topic further you
can deep dive into this and access the
entire uncensored library of unified TV
linked below a membership to unified
gives you unlimited access to hundreds
of uncensored podcasts investigative
journalism pieces documentaries films
and content that was once available on
major streaming services like Netflix
but is now banned from the internet for
just $4.99 a month which is less than a
buck a day it's actually less than 50
cents a day you get access to all of it
your subscription also helps keep the
platform running free from censorship
and corporate influence please consider
supporting us and enjoy all of our
unfiltered thought-provoking content in
return